

**Phone**: 778-513-1277

E-mail: izazzubayer@gmail.com

Website: izazzubayer.github.io

**Education:** Simon Fraser University

# **PROFILE**

Well organised and qualified primary communicator with a years of experience. I can adapt my conversation style to suit the needs of diverse groups of individuals. As a experienced communicator I would be well-suited for any role that requires communication skills. I am enthusiastic and have always strived to do the best.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# WEB DEVELOPER & PROGRAMMER & DESIGNER

#### Self-Taught Programmer (2017-present)

- · Full stack web developer (certified).
- Trained 300+ students, developed 5 interactive & dynamic website.
- Implement python to access Web Apps, developed several python projects.
- Participated in group meetings, interviewed, delivered presentation during working on a Startup.
- Canva, Illustrator Cards/posters layouts, borders, logos, fonts, user interface.

# FRONT-END CASH HANDLING

#### Safeway (Aug 2019-present)

- Skilled at receiving and processing banking transactions.
- Knowledge of proper cash handling procedures.
- · Cash drawer maintenance.
- Attention to detail.

# CUSTOMER REPRESENTATIVE

#### Juz Trading (Jan 2016- Aug 2018) | Safeway | Photography | Web Dev

- Handle customer inquiries, questions, service request.
- Active listening, locate solutions for problems over the phone & in person.
- Helped company attain higher customer service rating.
- Fast paced customer service & built productive relationships with customers.
- · Meet and exceed monthly sales targets.
- Experience at working in a fast pace environment.

# PLANNING, ORGANIZING & HANDLING PAPERWORKS.

#### IT Club- MLIS (2018 Jan-July 2018)

- Communication Tutored & managed class of 300 students for 6 months.
- Founder & President of the club Organized, sorted files and folders of each student. Prepared detailed reports, analysis, syllabus and routine.
- Gained success at team management with my colleague and the school administration.

### SKILLS

#### LANGUAGES SPOKEN

#### 18 Years

- · English
- Bengali
- Hindi

# COMPUTER PROGRAMMING

#### Self-Taught Programmer (2017-present)

- Web Developer- Code in Html, Css and Javascript, implementing all other modules such as Bootstrap, NodeJS, JQuery, SQL, MangoDB etc using Atom IDE.
- App Development Swift in Xcode & Java in Android Development Kit
- C++ and Java programming language
- · Algorithms & Data Structure.

## PHOTOGRAPHY, EDITING-LR & PS, & ONLINE MARKETING

#### Passion (2016-present)

- Knowledge on photography, angles, perspective, lenses, gear, aperture, depth of field etc.
- Years of experience in Adobe Lightroom and Photoshop and sold my presets online. Sold posters, photobook, planning on selling course.
- Managing my instagram account with a daily growing number of followers, also featured on UBC, SFU, Urba Vancouver and many more accounts for my photographs.
- Winner (2x) of photography competition at SFU for bokeh photography.
- Google SEO Marketer (Certified).

### COMMUNICATION

#### Learned from experience, books, real life interaction & podcasts

- Careful lesson planner keep all records presentable and updated.
- Active Listening, Clarity and Concision convey message in few words.
- Excellent ability to engage with individuals.
- Friendly, motivated and confident I don't let my personal problems interfere with my professional life.
- Empathy & Feedback I listen to people empathetically, acknowledge others' opinions, and provide response accordingly.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

#### 2014 - present

- Achieved 1st place in "Annual School Science Fair" in School Built smart mirror project from Raspberry Pi.
- Certification from Code Academy for coding an App within 1 hour.
- · Certification from "Jaago Foundation" for volunteering in humanitarian work.
- Won "Maces Personal Statement" Writing Competition recognized in UK.
- Certified Google Digital Marketer mastering SEO marketing strategy.
- Certified Python Programmer from Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MITx).
- Won photography contest in SFU on Depth Photography.
- Certified Udemy Full Stack Web Developer Mentored by Angela Yu (The App Brewery, London).
- Personal Startup Project.